V lands are virtual separations within a switch
and are used mainly to limit broadcast traffic.
A V land can be configured to communicate with other V
lands or not and may be used to segregate network segments.
There are a few common uses of V lands in corporate networks.
The first is to separate voice over I PV O IP telephones from the corporate network.
This is most often done to more effectively manage the network traffic generated
by voice communications by isolating it from the rest of the network.
Another common use of V
lands in a corporate network is to separate
the data center from all other network traffic.
This makes it easier to keep the server to server traffic contained to the data
center network while allowing certain traffic from
workstations or the web to access the servers
as briefly discussed earlier. V
lands can also be used to segment networks.
For example,
A V land can separate the payroll workstations from
the rest of the workstations in the network.
Routing rules can also be used to only allow devices within this payroll va
to access the servers containing payroll information.
Earlier, we also discussed network access control
nec
these systems use V LS to control whether devices connect
to the corporate network or to a guest network.
Even though a wireless access controller may attach to
a single port on a physical network switch.
The VL associated with the device connection
on the wireless access controller determines the va
that the device operates on and to which networks it is allowed to connect.
Finally, in large corporate networks,
V lands can be used to limit the amount of broadcast traffic within a network.
This is most common in networks of more than
1000 devices and may be separated by department location,
building or any other criteria as needed.
The most important thing to remember is that while V lands are logically separated,
they may be allowed to access other V lands,
they can also be configured to deny access to other V lands.